

# MAROOF BUTT

FILM DIRECTOR/FILM EDITOR

+92 333-4596479



619 A-1 Block Johar Town, Lahore



maroofbutt1993@gmail.com

#### **SOCIAL MEDIA**



https://linktr.ee/Maroofbutt



## **ABOUT ME**

I am a professional and ambitious filmmaker. I am highly skilled in direction, wiritng, cinematography and editing. I've worked on short film projects as well as directed short films. I am working as an executive video editor in a well known clothing hrand

# **EDUCATION**

- Matriculation // Computer Science
  - Beaconhouse School System
  - **(**) 2010-2012
- Intermediate // Fine Arts
  - Appeared as private candidate
  - O 2012-2014
- **BA(Hons) Film & Television** 
  - The University Of Lahore
  - **©** 2015-2019

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

2014-2015 Pakistan **PHOTOGRAPHER** / Youth Development Corps

Worked in this society to capture some of the most important seminars held by the students. Guest speakers included were

government officials, motivational speakers, independent filmmakers and writers.

· Capturing interesting moments and making them memorable for the society and institution.

· Asset management.

2016-2017

Pakistan

**DIRECTOR & EDITOR /** Anniemarie Schimmel Haus &

Rafi Peer Cultural Center

Got selected from my batch by the head of department. Met with the german filmmaker Marc Brummund and other students from prestigious institutes. I got involved in the creative process of pitching the perfect ideas and shaping them into an advertisement for Pakistan Red Cross Society.

- · Made the best possible frames.
- Editing.
- · Sound Design.
- · Sound Mixing.

2016-2017 Pakistan VIDEOGRAPHER, PHOTOGRAPHER & EDITOR / Training Impact

Worked with this organization, which is a leading corporate training and consulting firm. A great platform to test your abilities, team building and learn what it takes to be a leader.

- · Captured amazing moments in the wilderness and some of the intense moments as advised by the management.
- · Editing the event highlights as per the requirements of management.
- · Asset Mangement.

#### **EXPERTISE**

- Direction
- Editing
- Writing
- Cinematography
- Sound Design

#### **SKILLS**

Premiere Pro

Photoshop

After Effects

**Audition** 

Creativity

Leadership

**Problem Solving** 

**Teamwork** 

**Quick Learning** 

### **INTERESTS**

- Travelling
- Music
- Movies
- Books
- Photography

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE CONTINUED**

2016-2017

VIDEOGRAPHER & EDITOR/ Rafi Peer Cultural Center

Pakistan

Worked with Pakistan's leading cultural center. Mr. Imran Peerzada gave me this oppurtunity to shoot one of the best music festivals and record the mastero Ashraf Sharif Khan and Viktor Marek.

- Planned the shoot with Mr.Imran Peerzada and my fellows.
- Made sure that everything is according the plan.
- · Shot and Edited the event as guided.

2018-2019

ASSISTANT DIRECTOR & EDITOR / Storytellers

Pakistan

Worked with these talented people who were passionate to make Pakistan's First Digital Sitcom "GARAM ANDAY". I was involved in the creative process of Editing and assisted the director

- Helping the team with shot divisioning and sound recording.
- · Managing all the shoot data.
- Selecting the shots that are visually better.
- · Sound Treatment.
- · Sound Design.
- ADR (Automated Dialogue Replacement).
- · Color Grading.

2019-2020

EDITOR / Visual Prophecy

Pakistan

Worked with a well known production house. I was involved in the filming process and post-production. Editing as per client's demand. Working with sound designers as well as color grade artist.

- Selecting the good takes and cutting them into rough timeline.
- · Securing the shoot data.
- Meeting the clients and working with other artist to meet the requirments.

2020-Present

Pakistan

EDITOR / Intermoda Brands (Lulusar)

I am working with a well known clothing brand. I am involved in the research process. Editing the content as per brand guidlines.

- Sharing ideas for shoot.
- Sharing edit references.
- Creatively plan and execute the edit process as per campaign requirements..
- Animation and Graphics.
- · Color Grading.
- · Sound Design.
- · Maintaining sound libraries.
- Archiving of completed projects.